Aaron Parisi

Web Developer

I am a Web Developer based in Seattle, WA, with a passion for building web applications that focus on intuitive user experiences. With my background in Mathematics and experience as a Calculus teacher, I strive to use my analytical and technical abilities to help others.

- Seattle, WA
- 518.573.3522
- https://www.aaronparisi.dev
- parisi.aaron@gmail.com
- in aaron-parisi
- aaronparisi
- aaron-parisi

EDUCATION

AppAcademy

(May 2020 - February 2021)

Full Stack Web Development

- · Object Oriented Design in Ruby
- HTML & CSS
- Database Design & Querying Techniques using MySQL and PostgreSQL
- Data Structures & basic Algorithmic **Analysis**
- RESTful Application Design & MVC Paradigm in Rails
- Functional & Asynchronous Programming in JavaScript
- Frontend Rendering using React
- Frontend State Management using Redux

Northeastern University

(January 2016 - May Computer Science Bridge

- Introduction to Functional Programming
- Data Structures & Discrete Mathematics

Hartwick College Bachelor's Degree

Coursework

Mathematics, Economics

(September 2010 -May 2014)

3.9

2016)

- Discrete Mathematics
- Linear Algebra
- Abstract Algebra
- Real Analysis
- **Number Theory**
- Econometrics
- **SKILLS**

Ruby	Rails
JavaScript	React
Redux	SQL
HTML	css
Docker	Git
zsh/bash	AWS S3
AJAX	React D3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Plaid, Inc.

Technical Support Engineer

(August 2021 - Present)

- Investigated issues on behalf of Plaid clients, including connectivity failures and 400 errors, incorrect data in API endpoint response, and OAuth, MFA, and credentials issues
- Examined Plaid logs for HTTP error codes, request and response parameters, and JSON data
- Executed SQL queries on Plaid database tables to find trends and scope issues
- · Examined Plaid source code to discover, diagnose, and correct bugs
- Opened, searched, and appended Jira tickets
- · Communicated Plaid documentation, API behavior, and troubleshooting techniques to developers attempting to integrate with Plaid

Northeastern University

Computer Science Tutor

(September 2017 - December 2017)

(September 2014 - May 2015)

· Tutored grad students in Intro to Functional Programming at Northeastern University's Seattle campus

and Probability & Statistics to high school juniors and seniors

Salisbury School

Mathematics Teacher

· Taught Advanced Placement Calculus BC, Multivariable Calculus,

PROJECTS

CouponVision

https://www.coupons.aaronparisi.dev

- Generated a large dataset of grocery store product coupon data using data.world's grocery store data
- Built a Rails API:
 - Customized database seeding schema, JSON object return data, and API endpoints
- Built several interactive data visualizations using React and D3
 - Line Chart showing number of active coupons over time per grocery store chain
 - Stacked Bar Chart showing distribution of coupon brands among grocery store chains
 - · Tile Charts showing total savings available across brands

Springfield BnB

https://www.springfield-bnb.aaronparisi.dev

- . Built with a React+Redux frontend and a Rails API, this Simpsons-themed Air BnB clone features AWS S3 image storage & frontend authentication
- Configured API to accept CORS requests from both local and live frontends
- Addressed AWS configuration and secret key exposure

Towers of Hanoi Al Demo

https://www.towers.aaronparisi.dev

- · Created an interactive demo version of Towers of Hanoi that relies on ES6 promise syntax and implements the recursive solution to the game
- · Designed and implemented intuitive mouseover features using jQuery

https://www.todos.aaronparisi.dev

- Bundled a standard Todos app with Webpacker and some customizations to package.json
- Blended Rails erb views with pure React components
- Made database queries using Axios and ES6 promise syntax

... and many more!

https://www.aaronparisi.dev